Hello everyone and welcome back
to another lesson here at English pod.
My name is Marko and my
name is Catherine and today
We're talking about a topic
very close to my heart music.
That's right We're going to be talking
about music and more specifically we are
going to talk about musical
instruments that you would use in a band
All right, and so some people like to
Make their own music get
together hang out play music
together, so that's what
we're talking about today
I've got a new band that's going
to start and before we get going
We've got a word
to talk about and let's
check this out in today's
vocabulary preview
Very cablery preview
All right, so as I mentioned we
are going to talk about instruments
So you could say musical
instruments, but what is an instrument
generally speaking?
Basically, it's similar to a tool
Right, so an instrument is
something that you use to help you
Realize a task in this case musical
instruments is more specific, right?
Right, so we're talking about
things that you use to make music a
Piano for example is a
musical instrument or the drums
All right, so this is what we're
going to be looking at today
in the dialogues. So let's
listen to it for the first time
I'm forming a music band. Do you
already know how to play an instrument?
Yeah, I told you a thousand
times that I'm learning
to play the drums now that know how to
play well I would like to form a rock band
Aside from yourself who are
the other members of the band.
We have a guy who plays
guitar and another who plays bass
Although we still haven't
found anyone to be our singer
You told me that you had some musical
talent, right? Yes, I'm a singer perfect
So you can audition this
weekend here at my house
great
Wait here. You don't
have enough room for
the amplifiers microphones
or even your drums
By the way, where if you
keep them or practice?
Dude, what are
you talking about?
It's right here. All we need is
my Nintendo Wii and we're set
All right, we're back so
Apparently the band wasn't really a
real band. It wasn't but I have to say
I'm very familiar with
this because I have a
Nintendo Wii and I often
play the game rock band
So I can sympathize with the characters.
So you also have your own band.
I do well virtually
speaking and I know you do
That's right, we are both
fans of this of this game and
this gaming console and that's
why it's such a fun dialogue
But let's take a look at
some of the language that
was used in this dialogue
in language takeaway
Language takeaway
Oh man, so I've been
in a lot of bands and
I've been in a lot of a
lot of musical groups
So I can say that the
first instrument we want to
talk about is maybe the
most obnoxious the most
Wow, I'm hard to listen to probably
probably and that instrument is the drums
Right, so the drums it's plural because
you have many drums right right?
You don't just have the
dumb dumb dumb right the
bass drum you have many
different drums together
And so we could also call this a
drum set a drum set. All right, so
why don't we listen to an example
of what a drum set sounds like?
I
All right, we're back, so I think that's
clear moving on to our next instrument
This one's maybe the most
popular for young people to
start because you can play
pretty much anything with it
And it's also good for sing-alongs right
and that instrument is the guitar Mm-hmm.
Can you play the guitar? No, I can't
I actually wish I would have learned
But I never got around to it.
Well, this is a really beautiful
instrument and there are
many different ways to play it
But generally it's either wooden
with some strings or electric so it's
Plastic with some some metal strings right
exactly so they have a different sound
But why don't we listen to an
example of what a guitar sounds like?
All right, so great example
of a guitar pretty clear.
What's our next instrument
the bass and this one
It doesn't look like the
word that's written B-A-S S so
we say bass bass and it's
actually very low instrument
It's usually used to to help keep
the rhythm don't don't don't all right
So it's it's similar to a guitar
right very it's the same form
But as you say it's lower and it
makes a lower sound. Mm-hmm.
Exactly. All right, so let's listen
to an example of a bass now
All right pretty clear moving on to
our next word we have an amplifier
Okay, so amplifier an amplifier is a thing
It's usually a box that
we plug in it's electric
or it's electronic and
it's a tool to make
Electrical instruments
like the electric guitar
or the electric bass
louder right exactly so any
An amplifier is any device that makes
a sound become louder exactly all right
So this is really important for
rock bands the world over very
good our next instrument or
actually more of a tool is very useful
For the singer yeah, and it
actually goes with the amplifier
in many ways because the
microphones is our next word
The microphone is something that you
use to sing into to make your voice louder
So right now Marco you and
I are both using microphones
exactly so a microphone very
good and we have one last word
And this is a verb to
audition all right to audition so
To addition means to
show someone your talent.
All right, so oftentimes
when you start a
Play or an opera or a musical group
You want to have Auditions you
want to audition people to see
how much how much
talent they have all right
So it's basically an opportunity
to demonstrate your skills and
abilities exactly so in a job
interview wouldn't really be in audition
No job interview has its own its
own word, but here we're talking
about your singing ability your
acting ability your reading ability and
Sometimes we even have auditions
here at at English pot to see how people
How comfortable people
are on the microphone?
It's a way to to have people
show what they've got very good
All right, so a lot of interesting
words here many instruments
I think it's time for us to
listen to our dialogue again
We're gonna slow it down a
little bit and we'll be right back
I
'm forming a music band
Do you already know
how to play an instrument?
Yeah, I told you a thousand
times that I'm learning
to play the drums now that know how to
play well I would like to form a rock band
Aside from yourself who are
the other members of the band
We have a guy who plays
guitar and another who plays bass
although we still haven't
found anyone to be our singer
You told me that you had
some musical talent, right?
Yes, I'm a singer perfect. So you can
audition this weekend here at my house
Great
Wait here. You don't
have enough room for
the amplifiers microphones
or even your drums
By the way, where do
you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are
you talking about?
It's right here. All we need is
my Nintendo Wii and we're set
All right, we're back so
moving on with our lesson
Why don't we take a look now
at some phrases in fluency builder
Fluency builder
All right, so on fluency builder we
have four phrases. What's the first one?
Well, this first phrase is really
important Marco because we're
talking about bands and
starting bands and so there's often
A phrase we use to describe this. We say to
form a band. All right, so you form a band
It's like Forming something
to form is to shape it to make it
look like something that
you want and so we can form
Artistic projects also, but
he were forming a band.
We're choosing people to bring
together to make great music
All right, so we can
save form a band or you
can say as well start
a band. Yeah, all right
So and so we're forming a
band and well his friend was
surprised that the the other
guy knew had a plane instrument
So he said I've told you a thousand times
wait wait, so he told him 1,000 times no
Not literally an instrument I play an
instrument I play an instrument right
This is a phrase and it's a
little bit of an exaggeration to
emphasize that I've told you
many many times already great
So this is something we say when we're
trying to exaggerate like Marco said or to
To really emphasize the point
that like I've told you this before
So mothers often use it.
I feel like we talk about mother's life
Mothers often use this phrase
When kids do something wrong.
I say I told you a thousand times
Not to wear your shoes in the house
Exactly, so it is a great
phrase to to really make
your point that you've said
something many many times
Moving on we have a kind
of like a conjunction that
you can use and it's by
the way to change the topic
Maybe by the way by the
way and so by the way we
keep these words
together. It's a fixed phrase
By the way is something
we add on so I say you
know today went to school
and I saw a lot of people
Oh by the way John says hi
All right, so while I'm talking
about this I want to add
that this thing happened or
that this person said something
Exactly, so it is it's a conjunction
right to put together two different ideas
By the way or you can start off
your sentence with it by the way
How is the new house? Oh?
Because it's like it's like saying oh this
thought just came into my head by the way
Ta-da-da-da-da right right and our last
phrase on fluency builder is we are set
All right all we need is my
Nintendo we and we are set all right
So what what are we
set we are set all right?
We are set as another one of those phrases
it's fixed and it literally it means
And we are ready to
start we're ready to go and
everything is ready. Yeah,
we don't need anything
else And so Marco I
could say to you just bring
Just bring the salad to the table
and we're set. We're ready to eat.
All right, and I think we're set to
listen to our dialogue for the last time
And we'll be right back and talk a
little bit more about this great topic
I'm forming a music band. Do you
already know how to play an instrument?
Yeah, I told you a thousand times
that I'm learning to play the drums now
They know how to play well.
I would like to form a rock band
Aside from yourself who are
the other members of the band
We have a guy who plays
guitar and another who plays bass
although we still haven't
found anyone to be our singer
You told me that you had
some musical talent, right?
Yes, I'm a singer perfect. So you can
audition this weekend here at my house
Great wait here. You
don't have enough room for
the amplifiers microphones
or even your drums
By the way, where if you
keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you
talking about? It's right here
All we need is my
Nintendo Wii and we're set
All right, we're back so rock
band now. I know that you
can play a real instrument
not only instruments on the Wii
True what do you play?
I played the trumpet.
I was basically trained.
I started when I was
10 now is this the
trumpet that has the three
buttons on the top
three pistons three pistons
because there's another
one that doesn't right
There's one that has four pistons.
It's a piccolo trumpet has four and
There's one that's large and it slides
in and out and that's a trombone
That's much lower right, right, but the
trumpet is kind of a mid-range instrument
You can go quite high and
a little bit low and it's brass.
It's not wood. It's
made of a metal.
Right It's a it
looks like gold right
All right, so a you you play the trumpet
that you play in a in a band or in a yeah
I played in college in
high school middle school
and high school I played
in bands and orchestras
And in college I played in
orchestra and I've also played
in rock bands because sometimes
people want to you know
Have a trumpet and go a
little crazy nice interesting
This is interesting
because I'm sure a lot of
our users out there
actually play instruments
And maybe a lot of
them are also good at it
So come to Englishpot.com
leave your questions and comments
and let us know if you play
any instruments or maybe some
Strange instruments like the
xylophone or if you like to play we
rock band because we certainly
do and we can we can support you
We can give you some
tips. Yeah. All right, so
we'll see you guys there
until next time. Bye. Bye